What if I told you that the biggest
danger to your computer isn't a virus,
but a completely legal signed file?
Lately, I've been obsessed with this
thing called vulnerable driver. And to
show you how dangerous they really are,
I analyzed a highlevel game cheat. And
guess what? It uses a vulnerable driver.
But what exactly a vulnerable driver and
why are we in danger? Normally when big
companies like Nvidia or keyboard
manufacturers they release a signed
driver file. CIS Windows signs it and
they have the excess of the kernel the
brain of our system. But sometimes
developer are making a mistake. They
live in a little bit open doors for
cheaters. When the hackers find this
back door they using it. Once they enter
that open door the game over. They can
bypass the anti-che systems, manipulate
the memory, messing with OS, and doing a
bunch of stuff. In this video, I'm going
to reverse engineer a game sheet to show
you on action. But listen, it's not just
about gaming. If you have a company and
your worker falls for this and download
a cis file, you are really in danger.
Your company in danger. So, let's get to
work. All right, we are on Windows 10. I
know it's getting old, but I've been
tracking this cheat for years and I
don't think the developer is trying to
upgrade it anymore. Let's look at his
cheat website. He shares it and gamers
buy it. They download it to their
systems in a specific online game. By
the way, the name is randomized. When
you download the.exe, it keeps changing
its name. That's the first step of
hiding. In this video, we are going to
hide and seek with this cheat.
First of all, how can we understand the
level of this cheat sheet? Let's check
it out. I can't close it no matter what
I do. Task manager doesn't work against
it at all. When I try to reboot my
system, it throws a blue screen, a
kernel level error. So, for the rest of
the video, we are going to track this
sheet and let's see if we can find out
and protect our system. First off, when
we run this cheat, we see that we only
have a panel. This panel is the cheats
control center. It needs to load a
signed vulnerable driver. To do that, it
has to write the driver into our disk,
even just for a split second. For this,
I'm using a process monitor, also known
as procman, from Microsoft CIS internals
suit. Cheats usually using a drop and
load technique. They drop a vulnerable.
CIS file into our system, load it into
the Windows kernel, and immediately
delayed it to hide their tracks. Procman
is fast enough to catch that exact
millisecond. I'm setting up a citric
filter so we don't get lost in millions
of normal Windows events. Process name
contains cheat name path ends with cis
operation contains write file.
Okay, the trap is set. I start the
capture and run the sheet. I'm waiting
for that specific file creation event to
pop up on the screen. But the result,
nothing at all, completely empty. This
is frustrating, but actually it's a huge
clue. It tells us that the cheat isn't
just dropping a standard driver to the
disk like we expected. It might be a
fully memory based injection or it's
hiding behind the legitimate process
from the very beginning. Moving on to
another method process hacker. We are
seeing some colors here. The meaning of
them is purple, gray and orange. When I
search here, I can't find any suspicious
process. But here is the important part.
We are not just seeking for a process.
We had to check the drivers too. There
is a tab called services. I'm opening
that option called key modified time to
see what has changed, what is download
to our systems lately. But there is
nothing here either. But I have another
idea. Since this window exists, we need
to find it, right? We are going to use
find window to locate the process this
window belongs to. The results is pretty
surprising. The cheat is embedded inside
the desktop window manager known as
DWM.exe.
The cheat is currently injected into it.
We call this hijacking. It also prevents
me from inspecting the memory. In this
case, the cheat might be running a
command like stripe the handle rights of
anyone who tries to access DWM.exe
process. If we can't do that either,
let's move on. YD Arc. This program is
designed to see kernel hooks and hidden
files that standard tools can detect.
Here is the original GitHub link.
I downloaded it. Now we opened YDR. We
are looking at hundred of drivers
because normally Windows uses more than
500 drivers. Our goal is to find the
newly arrived foreign driver or the one
acting abnormally within this crowd.
First, we need to head over the kernel
tab at the top. This is the VIP area of
Windows. Once you're there, click on the
system callbacks or notify routin
section. Why here? Because modern game
cheats are low to set up a hooks in this
exact area to protect their processes
from being scanned. Now it's time to
hunt. Scroll through this list and keep
your eyes peeled for a few massive red
flags. Why the arc is quite helpful
here. It often highlights hidden or
manipulated hooks in red. We are
specifically looking for entries where
the module name is completely missing or
it just shows a random memory address
instead of a normal. CIS file. Also, pay
close attention to the company or serer
columns. If you spot an unsigned driver,
a weird string of random letters, or a
blank space where verified Microsoft or
hardware or vendor name should be,
bingo. But we are not on our lucky day.
There's empty. Another method is network
sniffing. Maybe the cheat didn't embed
the driver to the.exe file and pulling
it from the internet instead.
Considering the possibility, I choose
the listen network traffic. TCP view for
this. It looks a little bit complicated,
but there are important things that we
had to check first. Process name, who is
talking? Remote address, who is it
connecting to? and remote port. Which
port is it using to exit? But there is
no suspicious activity here either. Here
is the next method. Since we can catch
it alive, let's catch a dead. But what
does that mean? I mentioned earlier that
if you try to shut down your computer,
you get a blue screen. The exact second
window crashes with blue screen, they
take a snapshot to everything happening
in RAM and saves it to the disk as a
dump file called memory dmp. I'm
installing windbug to read this file.
This is the program that will analyze
the dump. But when it's time to collect
the crash records, I made a big mistake.
I doubt my space will be enough, but it
wasn't. After the first crash, I
couldn't find the memory. DMMP file. I
inspected the event viewer to find loss
file. And guess what? Your c disk
capacity must be the 5% of the complete
disk space. So be careful about that or
just click on that check box when you
need a memory. DMP file. So let's get to
work. I shut down the computer and get
the crash.
Collected the DMP file and run the
analyze command.
Guess what I found? As you can see,
there is a bug check code 1E, which is
the error code on the blue screen that
we get. And there is bug check P1. It
means a program running deep in kernel
mode tried to read or write to a memory
address it had absolutely no permission
to touch. Now, let's look at the biggest
discovery of our analyszis. Look closely
at the buck check P2 line reveals that
exact memory address where the crash
actually happened. Notice what missing.
Normally Windbug shows a model name
right next to this address like a
standard cyis file. But here there is
absolutely nothing. No name, no file. So
let's continue. This is the proof of the
injection that we talked about earlier
at the process hacker. So since we find
the exact location of the memory address
that causes of the crash, what is
actually happened? I'm typing these
commands to see that and I'm just saying
be ready for this. This is a lack
mechanism used in multi-threading
programming. The cheat locks the system
to prevent data conflicts while it's
simultaneously reading the game's memory
and writing data to the interface. When
you close the cheat, suddenly its
location in the memory was wiped out.
But that hidden thread it left behind
was still running and it tried to lock a
deleted memory address. The moment it
touched the void, Windows crashed the
system to protect itself. This is the
VIP memory area of the Windows kernel
that says never write to disk. Always
stay in RAM. The cheat intentionally
carved itself in here to avoid
performance drops and ensure high-speed
reading. Instead of dropping a CIS file
around, the cheat developer went
straight to the kernel manager which
manages Windows own processes and
created a fake system thread for
themselves. This is exactly why we
couldn't find anything in YDRC process
hacker because there is no driver at
all. The cheats infiltrated directly
into the Windows threats and was
operating like a ghost. So what we
learned the traditional anti-che systems
is trash. Reading the disk and saying
this is the suspicious file is trash. We
are facing of new level cheating.
Cheaters injecting directly into the
Windows being the Windows itself. As we
proved in this video, there is no file.
The cheat is fileless. It doesn't leave
a cis file like the normal cheats. It
hides its code directly into the
memory's deepest area which is ring
zero. This is exactly why modern games
loves to use kernel level and tie sheet
into our system because this is the new
level. Okay, so people are mad about the
FPS game called Valerance Vanguard
anti-che system. is the kernel level and
takes a huge excess in our memory in our
Windows OS. So people are mad about this
but look at that. Look just what we
found. So yeah, that's all. Thank you
for watching.